Sinan Cengiz

sinancengiz_84@hotmail.com | 415-767-6234 | San Francisco, California

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sinan-cengiz-4a53246b/

Github: https://github.com/sinancengiz | Website: https://sinancengiz.github.io/

SUMMARY

Highly analytical and process-oriented data analyst with in-depth knowledge of database types; research methodologies; and big data capture, curation, manipulation and visualization. Furnish insights, analytics and business intelligence used to advance opportunity identification, process reengineering and corporate growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python,R, MySQL,Tableau, JavaScript, GIT, Github, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, the command line, computer science fundamentals

PROJECTS

TalentSource | Python, Flask, Pandas, SQLJavaScript, D3, Plotly | **Github** | Data application for analyzing employee data source in a company

- Analyzed employee data for a company and provide information and outcome with the desired criteria
- Used Python, Flask, Pandas, SQL, JavaScript, D3, Plotly

Titanic AI (Predictive Modeling) Python, Sklearn, ML, Flask, Pandas, SQLAlchemy, SQLite, JavaScript, D3, Plotly | **Github**

Application to predict users survival by running machine learning model

- Predicts users survival or not survival outcome using by training a Support Vector Machine models based on observed users input
- · Saved prediction data to database and updated in real-time data visualizations and chart

EXPERIENCE

Relationship Banker – Bank of America Sales Representative – Zip Marketing Inc Assistant Librarian – Lincoln University April 2017 – December 2017 May 2016 - Jully 2016 October 2015 - May 2016

EDUCATION

University of California at Berkeley – Data Science Bootcamp Lincoln University – Master of Science International Business Beykent University – Master of Business Administration Anatolian University –Bachelor's Economics August 2018 December 2017 July 2013 July 2010

PUBLICATIONS

An Empirical Study Including Implication of Modern Management Theories http://www.ajbmr.com/articlepdf/aus-29-180i03n12a2-d.pdf